{
    "id": "0b3722eef09f43f386675dabe8612e43",
    "title": "Adjectives And Adverbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She worked ……………………….. and passed the examination.",
            "description": "Hard is an adverb. Hardly is also an adverb, but it has a very different meaning. It is similar to scarcely. ",
            "answers": [
                "hard",
                "hardly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e52c7793d21847829442977c998695ff"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am …………………………… about this.",
            "description": "Very is normally used without much before adjectives and adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "very sorry",
                "very much sorry",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ea98bcde95694649b09e94eeafba15e9"
        },
        {
            "question": "The movie was ……………………….. interesting.",
            "description": "Too has a negative meaning. It means more than is necessary or required. So and very are possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "so",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bd8207da915a4d9bb4508b7cbf435a93"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. his father closely.",
            "description": "There is no preposition between resemble and its object.",
            "answers": [
                "resembles",
                "resembles to",
                "resembles with"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fae3cf1e3fc74728b5eb3d8f956234ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly ……………………………. any rest since one week.",
            "description": "Hardly is a negative word. When a negative word or expression comes at the beginning of the sentence, it is followed by an inverted word order – that means the auxiliary goes before the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "I have had",
                "have I had",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "262d5766dedf433a81cd5867b4788f05"
        },
        {
            "question": "That boy does ………………………",
            "description": "Mischief is an uncountable noun. We use much to modify it.",
            "answers": [
                "much mischief",
                "many mischieves"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "08ae2b4305bd40ea8e461f9670bb2a8a"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is getting ……………………….. day by day.",
            "description": "Comparative form of the adjective is preferred here because there is an implied comparison between his present and previous states.",
            "answers": [
                "good",
                "well",
                "better"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8d43e2e199274c60873e00a0ea1c8370"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you disturb him, he ……………………………. get angry.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "would get",
                "would have got"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c980398acf2341fcb681f7db2d61bfa2"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better …………………………… another application.",
            "description": "Had better is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "send",
                "sent",
                "to send"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6c45a99ea306438c8642857ba6e30c38"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… across the field, I saw a dead horse.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Walking",
                "While walking",
                "While I was walking"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "12364592002e4dd991752b3b5750330e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rome was ……………………… by Romulus.",
            "description": "Found is the past and past participle form of find. Founded is the past participle form of found.",
            "answers": [
                "found",
                "founded"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "75bad8f9643c4921823f8031dcf4ae9c"
        },
        {
            "question": "His grandfather is ………………………….",
            "description": "Dead is an adjective and died is a verb. We need an adjective here because 'is' is a verb of incomplete predication. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "dead"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "67455588cc774ed9b61be138c1e0b494"
        }
    ]
}